[Music]
thank you
hello and welcome to preview Prime uh
you're watching talking point and my
guest today is bhavin Shah who is the
founder and fund manager at summature
Capital bhavin thank you very much for
joining us on BQ Prime uh let me begin
with uh you know when we spoke to you
last time you had highlighted that you
know there are Global headwinds which
are coming in form of inflationary
pressures and Central governments would
be taking action as he stand today we
have seen a lot of action taken by lots
of central governments uh where you see
this cycle of interest rate now you know
ebbing and uh you know returning to a
normalcy
so today if you see the recent data on
inflation uh I think we are starting to
see uh at least on a sequential basis uh
a significant fall in inflation
uh now you know in case of India core
inflation is still high uh but overall
inflation has started to come down and
in case of U.S you know month-on-month
data definitely suggest that inflation
is uh cooling off quite a bit and I
think it's all because of the you know
title monetary policies that have been
adopted as you know the interest rate
tightening included
um so I would I have to think that uh we
probably have seen the worst of the
inflation and uh while there could still
be uh you know one or two maybe one more
interested hike if if a particular
Central Bank wants to play safe the the
cycle of rate increases probably is
towards its end
um uh you know especially in the U.S you
know one of them the market is penciling
in there you know that rate hikes could
go on further till uh the FED receives
the uh you know uh Target level of two
two and a half percent of inflation
which they are a comfortable with uh as
compared to India where they are already
coming into the ban of four to six
percent and do you see how how do you
see this playing out in the for Global
uh equity and uh flows
I think the uh you know Global equities
uh in in India I mean I think yeah when
I uh when I look at the uh you know
Target inflation being two percent I
think you know I think if you look at
the sequential data it is definitely
suggesting that we are uh uh you know
kind of close to that number so uh uh
you know so I think uh that's that's the
backdrop if you look at the equity
valuations uh let's say you know we look
at us and India I mean I think we are uh
the uh in case of us the Schiller P
which kind of looks at a longer term
earnings uh normalized earnings and uh
you know on that basis it's sort of
close to an average level now
um
so I think only thing that I think you
know that suggests the valuations are a
bit stretched in case of us is the
market Capital GDP ratio which is still
high compared to the historical levels
um I think the other thing is that we
have seen while we have seen a lot of uh
cutbacks in employment in technology
sector there hasn't been as much in the
rest of the sector in the U.S economy so
it is possible that
we may actually have a Slowdown but not
a deep recession and I think Market may
start to think about that uh in you know
and and I think we might actually see a
better stock market in 2023 in us than
what we saw in 2022 I think probably uh
we might see a small increase this year
is what I feel
um as far as India goes um obviously our
markets have actually been sort of weak
for uh at least around 12 months there
has been primarily uh you know
appreciation in certain sectors and I
think even today what I feel is that it
is going to be uh you know a bit more of
a sector uh specific and stocks specific
situation in India we actually quite
like the
macroeconomic backdrop for India for
number of factors you know whether it's
the fiscal position of the government
you know the you know the tax
collections are very strong which I
think gives them breathing space to do
what they need to do uh to keep the
economy going you know the in inflation
I think is while the core inflation is
still a bit on a uncomfortable level uh
you know chances are that it might start
to come off a bit I think there are you
know the commodity inflation you know
the crude all that is favorable and I
think underlying economy in terms of
demand perspective looks pretty healthy
uh so uh with that in mind uh we might
you know might not see a big rally
because of where the valuations are
um and uh but I think uh one will find
number of opportunities in this market
across many sectors is what I feel you
know uh if if someone would have asked a
your back that you know outflow of 30
billion dollars from foreign investors
and the index would be at the same level
no one would have agreed to uh it's
primarily because of domestic flows
which have come in uh and that's holding
on the index at these levels how do you
see the domestic valuation picture
looking
um especially from the point of view as
you said macros are improving but at the
same time there is some pressure on
earnings which is which is which is
there so how do you see if you put both
of them together uh how the valuation is
looking for the domestic Market I think
see March 23 year we we probably saw a
lot of normalization and on you know and
margins some sectors especially where
there were a lot of uh one-off type of
effects whether it's covet benefit or
whether it's uh uh you know price
increases in some you know Commodities
those benefits obviously sort of kind of
reversed in 2000 f523 uh I think so
March 24 if you think about it by
looking a bit more of a normal year and
I think if the interest rate cycle is
sort of near its peak uh you know we
probably with a strong demand I think we
might see decent earnings growth as well
uh so overall I think the Market Outlook
is uh more positive definitely in my
view then again you know the calendar 22
uh what we saw but I think the uh well
I'm going to have to uh kind of find
Opportunities uh on and evaluate on a
case-by-case basis because what is
happening is the the breadth in the
market is increasing we are seeing so
many new listings so many IPOs
um you know the heading the uh and so
the money will you know while as you say
you know the domestic money has really
supported this Market there's a lot of
money that is also going into new uh
kind of sectors and new companies you
know last year a lot of money went into
public sector for example so that I
think process kind of uh might still
continue and so we may not see a
regularly in the overall index but I
think there will be a lot of
opportunities in specific companies or
sectors you mentioned about the public
sector money going to public set
companies or Nifty Bank was a good
example of that where Banks where the
ESU Banks narrowed its valuations with
respect to uh private sector do you see
there's enough steam left in PSU Banks
to go through for 23 24.
so I think when we look at what is
driving this uh kind of resurgent in PSU
bank and I think a lot of uh people have
kind of uh you know a lot of people got
in early and you know they support got
disappointed over the finally the PSU
sector PSP Bank you know public sector
banks have re-rated and what is what is
I think the fundamental reason is
obviously their balance sheets have
improved significantly uh but I think
also on an ongoing basis it seems that
the Reserve Bank is having a much
tighter watch on the numbers of all the
banks not just public sector Banks
so the risk of another big sort of uh uh
you know NPA crisis uh developing seems
rather low at this point and so it is
possible that and I think there seems to
be uh a lower level of interference in
the governing of the public sector Banks
so it is quite possible that while we
may not see the kind of rally that we
saw last year I think some more uh
appreciation in the public sector Bank
might continue because State still are
attractively valued relative to the
private sector Banks and so that you
know process may actually continue
missing
uh you know one of the sectors which
used to track very closely was it yeah
you've seen a large companies coming out
with earnings last week if TCS Infosys
HCL Tech uh and Wipro how do you read
into those earnings uh and do you see
some pain points emerging or initial
paying points emerging in those earnings
look the fear is there that you know and
I think the clear uh the clear kind of
linkage is that if U.S corporate profits
suffer uh the I.T spending you know
takes a you know impact and that
obviously translates to lower growth for
Indian ID companies so that relationship
you know I don't think it's gonna uh go
away though uh some of the uh
initiatives you know some other urgency
uh to invest in modern Technologies uh
may actually continue and as a result we
may not see as big a tip as one might
see but the the question is whether or
not whether there is going to be a you
know a meaningful erosion of corporate
profits and I think so far the signs are
not there and I think you know look at
the commentary of the companies also
they're still seeing a pretty decent uh
demand picture you know we have already
in you know middle you know sort of
middle of January uh so there has been
you know a lot of budget discussions
have already happened you know and I
think the so I can actually feel that we
might get slightly be positively
surprised with respect to growth demand
growth in the sector in the coming 12
months and that I think
while the the valuations are kind of
mixed you know there are some some I.T
companies which are attractively valued
uh I think the market is still not
believing in in their story in the sense
that they actually are talking about a
lot of structural improvements in the
market I think wants to see more of it
and so they are still available at good
prices whereas the the well-known names
are not that attractive however when we
compare the stocks in the ID sector with
the rest of the uh sectors in the Indian
market uh especially the companies with
similar quality of earnings similar
return on Capital similar you know
dividend payouts and similar growth
opportunity it sectors actually looks
very attractively valued yeah so you
know we have been very cautious on the
sector uh for some time but I think uh
going forward we might want to be a
little bit more uh positively biased is
what I would say
how do you see uh the large caps within
the IIT sector versus the mid cap
companies uh do you see a mid caps
they've been able to uh uh you know able
to handle the kind of you know
volatility that may come in uh in this
sector
I think see the what has happened is
that the IIT Outsourcing the offshore
model is so well established and uh and
and the quality and maturity
of execution you know the capabilities
in the mid-size company is also very
well evolved so we may not see uh like
mid cap companies suffering more than
the large cap and that kind of uh you
know Behavior may not be visible and I
think Market it's always reasonably
efficient about it and I think we are
seeing pretty decent uh you know
valuations also you know is of a good
quality media companies are not that
cheap actually so I would say that the
opportunity will primarily across large
or mid cap would be in companies which
may have had somewhat checkered history
in the past but for number of factors
they are actually uh likely to do better
in future you know those would be sort
of interesting turn around opportunities
for sure uh whereas you know the well
established names last year mid cap I
think they probably will still do okay
but not as well as some of this kind of
quote-unquote turnaround opportunities
if in your portfolio which is a sector
that you're overweight as of today
I mean uh I think you know we are very
uh I would say Diversified in our
portfolio so it is difficult for me to
tell you where I'm overweight uh you
know we have we have exposure to a whole
range of things uh uh you know I think I
don't think we are overweight per se I
think I don't think there is a reason to
be uh overweight in any sector you know
there are a number of opportunities
across many sectors I find there is one
in terms of number of uh names in the
sector we're quite interested in uh
space related to wealth management you
know you mentioned uh earlier in the uh
in our discussion how the domestic
investors supported the market even with
such a big outflow from foreign
investors so there are number of
companies in the wealth management space
uh actually relatively smaller companies
that are doing some really interesting
work and uh those companies are not yet
fully appreciated by the market in terms
of you know the way how the way they are
priced so we are seeing opportunities in
that space
uh you know
you your your benchmark against the BAC
fire 500 TR uh and that had a return of
4.7 for last one year uh compared to
your fund I think there is a marginal
tip there of two percent old if I'm not
wrong
um where is it under performance coming
in from which sector
I think we had uh underperformance from
uh from financials uh we had I think
very little participation in the public
sector sector uh so I think there was a
clear under performance from the public
sector space
so obviously under performance there as
well
um
tell me uh you know you were little
skeptical about the commodity and metals
uh last year when we spoke to you uh how
what is your view today on metals and
commodities
I think the the sector Outlook is
probably better now uh I think China uh
you know with a complete kind of opening
up you know removing all restrictions of
covet and we might see Improvement in
demand from that and that's that segment
um I think obviously globally there is
probably some risk of a Slowdown uh but
I think all that is sort of uh uh you
know probably priced in so the Outlook
would be a little bit you know
definitely better than what it was last
year though we don't have very big
exposure there you know it's a difficult
space for us to really cut out data and
get hold of so unless they see us you
know a real uh margin which is like
asset available below its replacement
value we Trend not not to invest there
uh you know have you changed your view
on the new age companies because that's
uh you you wear a little bullish on
those companies last year
um and they were holding games but today
in the last one year there has been a
lot of losses for those companies what's
your view on there and have you changed
your view on them
well we have you know first of all we
have uh you know we what we have said is
that while uh some of the newest
companies have business model that will
you know that will last and especially
with uh nice watches some of them have
they would definitely ride through the
uh kind of the phase of uh uh you know
basically losses uh but we have never
really uh kind of invested in that space
because we never really have found uh
attractive opportunities uh in that
space
um I mean even today I think uh the kind
of view is somewhat similar while there
has been Fair bit of correction I don't
think uh we are finding them you know
enough number of names where you know we
have reached a right point of valuation
with respect to what is the growth
opportunity but we will continue to I
think given the correction that will
happen you know we might some you know
maybe in the future we might find
something that is worth worth owning but
when you looked at the technology and
Tech space very closely
how do you look at these kind of
companies uh for an investor uh what
kind of parameters do you look and when
you say that it is uh they're going to
be still loss making but at some time
they have to start making cash flows
positive uh how do you uh value them at
what price do you think that you know
it's an inflection point for them uh for
anyone to identify
so I think what we are willing to do is
we are willing to look as far as
required to understand such company so
maybe the opportunity is over a spread
of next 25 years we don't mind thinking
about 25 years for such businesses if if
the idea is that you have to separate
say a mature part of the business versus
the new uh let's say they are well
established in one geography and the the
financials there are looking like uh you
know they are making money their you
know returns are starting to uh generate
you know the good returns for example in
on Capital we are willing to separate
that versus the new areas where they're
still investing and basically uh draw
from what they have achieved or what you
know to a kind of extrapolate for the
new areas of the new geographies or new
in uh kind of verticals where they might
be investing uh but after doing all that
it still has to make sense from a cash
flow standpoint
you know the cash flows may come five
years later that's okay but you know if
after making those assumptions if you're
not uh justifying it on the you know the
cost of capital that this business is
you know this after discounting those
future cash flows then we wouldn't
invest so how how do you look at some of
the companies I'm just going you're
throwing a name here for purpose of
discussion uh like a mama out there
right
um they are into fmcg but into online
space
uh when you look at an FNG
space you need to look at a traditional
one but because you're an online you
need to look at little differently so
how do you value such companies
no we still will evaluate uh like an
fmcg company uh as I said you know we
would look at their current phase of
investment try to you know kind of fast
you know go deep into uh
how long will that phase continue what
will be the ultimate uh you know the
scale we look at the size of the
opportunity how big is the potential of
opportunity that they have obviously
they might have have a potential to
expand into adjacent spaces and so on so
forth so we would try to do do all that
and but after that you know again you
know it will still boil down to whether
on a cash flow basis it makes sense even
as I said your cash flows can come five
years later seven years later that's
okay
uh and I think there's it is it is
similar to looking at even things like
say life insurance right because it's uh
you know a lot of Indian life insurance
companies are in a heavy growth phase
um but you know ultimately there has to
be earnings that has to be payout you
know that that sort of model has to work
eventually
even uh the public sector life insurance
company means do you do you have
exposure to that and do you compare that
uh with the private sector uh to before
you invest
so we have exposure to one of the public
sector life insurance companies which is
sort of very well you know their numbers
are fantastic the growth story is
excellent and you know they're very
comparable to private sector private
insurance company so we do have exposure
to uh you know one public sector life
insurance as well as one private sector
life insurance
because we see that a sector is a growth
sector you know the huge runway for
growth and uh so you know if the company
is well run and I think they've managed
the the you know the the risk very well
uh and you know the matrices such as you
know the persistency ratios are good you
know their ability to uh estimate their
embedded value is good in the sense that
they are not having to revise it down uh
as time goes all those factors we look
at and then you know and you know and
then if if it makes sense from valuation
standpoint we would invest it
uh you know just to come to an end of
the thing uh
we we saw the index giving again a four
to five percent last year in 2022. uh do
you see uh double digit uh returns
coming in in 23 for uh the index
uh what could be the challenges for that
20 double digit uh returns if at all
I think the challenge is that you know
the global economy you know goes through
a much deeper recession than what we
have uh what we think it will so that
would obviously affect some segments of
the Indian economy you know our export
part or the story will get affected
um so that was one risk that I can see I
think other than you know some kind of
event risk you know platform event that
Etc et cetera but no exception there I
think you know the output you know
higher returns in 2023 definitely is
there I wouldn't want to cast the number
uh because I don't I haven't honestly
done that work but yes I I think looking
at all the parameters it looks like we
could have a stronger year in uh
calendar 23 after India and from a macro
point of view you have some of the
challenges which are there which is
coming in plus a lot of states are going
for elections and then uh we are heading
towards the general election in uh early
first half of 2024. uh what kind of uh
Headway Headroom does using the
government has full with respect to
spending because last year the biggest
highlight for the budget was the capex
which the government announced we didn't
see that capex fully taking off in the
first half at least first nine months
we're hoping that you know in the last
three four months it will pick up but do
you see continued thrust on capex and do
you see for the Headroom for the
government to have to be there uh for
them to continuously invest
of in capex and other Investments I
think the the space is definitely there
for government to continue to uh push
the pattern on capex there is definitely
you know you know you look at all the
tax numbers you know the the financial
situation but you know it's pretty
looking pretty good so I would say that
they will continue that uh uh in in a
you know I think when we see the budget
I I expect them to continue to uh
support capex uh because I think they
have uh you know very you know a lot of
ambitious plans and you know to complete
a lot of projects and I you know don't
see them slowing down I mean I think
also this is also a Statewide story and
I think what we are seeing is a healthy
uh bit of competition uh you know you
know across States the states that have
uh where governments have done good job
with uh you know building infrastructure
you know capacity and you know I think
they've also got re-elected so you know
recently for example one of the state I
think Telangana where there is an
election coming as well I think they
talked about again about uh you know
infrastructure basically push as a kind
of a you know ahead of the election so
that is uh that uh you know the the the
the thought process the the language is
definitely uh supportive of uh you know
Central and state government continuing
the Gap exposure
it's been a pleasure today talking to
you thank you very much for joining us
on BQ Prime thank you thank you thank
you bye
[Music]
thank you